### ISMAIL HOSSAIN

Address: KA-57/2, Kuril Chowrasta, Vatara, Dhaka Primary Mobile No: 01705723616

Primary Email: hossain.wbs.dev@gmail.com



### **Career Objective:**

Computer Technology with over 6 years of experience, both technically focused and customer orientated. I am looking for a career that is both challenging and reward.

#### **Career Summary:**

My greatest passion and strong is Digital Marketing & Programming which is why I have chosen to make it my career and make a living out of it. I see preparing Digital Marketing strategy & Programming as a Hobby since it is an evolving, dynamic process which always full of surprises.

Above all, I want to develop my Digital Marketing & Programming skills under seniors. & now it``s become my innate nature that to be a great Digital Marketing Expert & Programmer in future.

### **Employment History:**

Total Year of Experience: 9.4 yrs

1. Web Developer (1.5 yrs)

(May, 2021 - Continuing)

ilannoor Edification Ltd.

Baridhara

**Area of Expertise** 

Web Design and Development (1.5 yrs)

#### **Duties/Responsibilities**

Responsible for the companyâ□□s Web Development & Digital Marketing strategies.

Project Manager of ilannoor.com & ilannoor.institute.

2. Web Developer (2.8 yrs)

(August, 2018 - May, 2021)

Freelancing

Area of Expertise

Web Design and Development (2.8 yrs)

### **Duties/Responsibilities**

Responsible for developing Website, Graphics & Social Media Marketing strategies.

3. Web Developer (1.3 yrs)

(March, 2017 - July, 2018)

DBN Ltd.

Uttara

### **Area of Expertise**

Web Development (1.3 yrs)

## **Duties/Responsibilities**

Responsible for the companyâ∏s Web Development, Graphics & Social Media Marketing strategies.

4. Web Developer (0.2 yr)

(October, 2016 - January, 2017)

## KiddoLand

Jamuna Future Park

### Area of Expertise

Web Development (0.2 yr)

### **Duties/Responsibilities**

 $Responsible \ for \ the \ company \^a \hbox{$\square$} \hbox{$\square$} \hbox{$\square$} \hbox{$Web} \ Development, \ Graphics} \ \& \ Social \ Media \ Marketing \ strategies.$ 

5. Marshal (0.2 yr)

(May, 2016 - July, 2016)

**British Council** 

## Area of Expertise

Management (0.2 vr)

## **Duties/Responsibilities**

- Complete all reports, logs and claims accurately and real time.
- Ensure that all test day procedures are met.
- To complete prescribed log sheets as directed by Exam Services.

## 6. Brand Promoter (0.1 yr)

(March, 2016 - April, 2016)

#### Ekhanei.com

#### **Area of Expertise**

Brand Marketing (0.1 yr)

#### **Duties/Responsibilities**

- Responsible for the companyâ□□s Brand promoting strategy.
- Adds posting on Ekhanei.com

## 7. Web Developer (0.2 yr)

(November, 2015 - January, 2016)

### **Kernel BD Corporation**

Kuril Progoti Sharani

### **Area of Expertise**

Web Developing (0.2 yr)

### **Duties/Responsibilities**

Responsible for companyâ∏s Web Development strategy.

#### 8. Online Marketing (1.9 yrs)

(September, 2013 - August, 2015)

#### CreativacIDA

Bashundhara

#### Area of Expertise

Lead Genaration (1.9 yrs)

#### **Duties/Responsibilities**

- Overall responsibility for the companyâ [] S Online marketing strategy. BR- Adds posting on USA Classified site for generating leads.

## 9. Online Marketing (0.5 yr)

(February, 2013 - August, 2013)

## Upwork

Bashundhara

#### Area of Expertise

Lead Genaration (0.5 yr)

### **Duties/Responsibilities**

- Adds posting on USA Classified site for generating leads.BR- Working section on housing, for sale, services & jobs etc.

## **Academic Qualification:**

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pas.Year
Diploma in Engineering	Computer Science & Engineering	National Polytechnic		2014
		Institute,Dhaka		
SSC	Commerce	Abdul Khaleque Memorial High	Second Division,	2010
		School	Marks :3.75%	

## **Career and Application Information:**

Looking For : Top Level Job Available For : Full Time Expected Salary : Tk. 30000

Preferred Job Category : Engineer/Architect, IT/Telecommunication

Preferred District : Dhaka

Preferred Organization Types : Software Company, IT Enabled Service, Web Media/Blog

### **Specialization:**

### Fields of Specialization

- Adobe Photoshop/ Illustrator
- Cpanel
- Digital Marketing
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- HTML5
- CSS3
- PHP
- LaravelGit Version Control System
- Bootstrap 5

### **Language Proficiency:**

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangla	High	High	High
English	High	High	Medium
Hindi	Low	Low	Medium

# **Personal Details:**

: Abul Kalam Azad : Saleha Begum : October 28, 1994 Father's Name Mother's Name Date of Birth

: Male : 0 : 62 : Married Gender Height (Meter) Weight (Kg) Marital Status Nationality Religion

. Dangiauesni : Islam : KA-57/2, Kuril Chowrasta, Vatara, Dhaka : Dhaka : B+ Permanent Address

**Current Location** Blood Group